# **Curriculum Vitae**

Name	Mr Alex Luton
E-mail	aluton@gmail.com
Telephone	07811 623 204
Web	http://starcross.eu

#### **Overview**

I am an experienced software developer and manager, currently available for new opportunities in London and the South-East. My strengths lie in building software by communicating effectively with both client and developers in combination with a strong technical underpinning. I advocate a platform and language agnostic approach, favouring the most appropriate tools for each solution.

## **Key Achievements**

#### Leadership of a web development team for 8 years

Managing developers, designers, and content editors, I have led an evolving team through a variety of successful web projects in a hands-on role.

### Management of a large organisational website portfolio

I managed the online portfolio of the Royal College of Surgeons from 2006-2014, growing and adapting to meet the demands of the digital sector. Now critical to the organisational profile and its business processes, the portfolio comprises around 15 sites with 2 million visits annually.

#### Development and management of ecommerce systems

I oversaw the creation and support of an ecommerce platform integrated with a bespoke CRM system. Having grown to serve all core areas of the business, annual transactions now exceed £8m.

## Management and development of an Intranet

I have iteratively developed an Intranet application over 10 years. This features bespoke employee tools such as timesheet recording, performance review management, and business planning.

Managing a complete redevelopment, I introduced a Knowledge Base concept, Forums and open CMS access to encourage collaborative information sharing and community building.

#### **Development of Clinical Data Entry Systems**

I have developed two web based secure data entry and reporting systems in 2003<sup>i</sup> and 2005<sup>ii</sup>, and project managed creation of another in 2008<sup>iii</sup>. These sites collected clinical data in a secure environment for research purposes, and to provide a data management facility for participating hospitals or data centres.

#### **Development of eLearning Web Applications**

I have managed the development of three iterations of a virtual learning environment style application<sup>iv</sup>. This comprised of database driven questions, tests, forums, and resources

## **Experience and Skills**

I have practised full life cycle development in both management and development roles with rewarding results. As an established developer, I prefer to work hands-on, leading by example when working with a team.

I have project managed software systems in varying environments with different methodologies including Prince2 and Agile inspired approaches. My experience and success has enabled me to contribute at a strategic level, able to gain confidence and influence senior management.

The core of my experience centres on multi-disciplinary development, incorporating a variety of tools and languages. Using both internal resources and external agencies, I have realised numerous complex systems with multiple stakeholders.

### Software development

- Multi-language developer with 12 years industry experience
- A passion for developing software from childhood
- Creative and visionary, prepared to test limits and build on experience
- Flexible and adaptable to a project's needs

### **Project Management**

- 8 years experience managing web projects
- Genuine interest and motivation in developing exceptional software
- Honest approach to planning and managing expectations
- Full commitment to building and supporting sustainable systems throughout their lifetime

#### Systems design and architecture

An intuitive grasp of recognising and developing elegant design solutions

## **Team Leading**

- Substantial experience leading a web development and support team
- Can easily mix with, support and encourage other developers

## **Systems analysis**

- Experienced at realising requirements into new and existing systems
- Able to factor cost, time, support, and technical constraints into development projects
- Comfortable using reporting tools such as Google Analytics and SQL to derive evidence based recommendations

#### Recruitment

- Recruitment and training for: development roles, content editing, and web design
- Aware of the professional market by working closely with agencies

## **Customer Support**

- Experience supporting internal and external customers
- Approachable, and able to work with non-technical users

## **Technology Background**

Domain Key Skills

Languages Python, C++, SQL, Java, PHP, C#, VB.NET, Ruby, Assembly,

Haskell

Web HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Responsive, Accessibility, Selenium,

jQuery, SOAP, SSO, SEO

Web Platforms Plone, Zope, Django, Apache

Methodologies PRINCE2, Agile

**Databases** MySQL, SQL Server

Source Control Git, Subversion

# **Employment**

Organisation	Location	Date	Job Title
The Royal College of	London	2006 –	Web Development
Surgeons of England		September 2014	Manager

The core of my experience at the RCS centres on software development, project management, and team leading. As the web manager I oversaw an ambitious development programme, and contributed to organisational strategy and policy.

2003 – 2006 Senior Web Developer

In this senior role I developed a variety of predominantly Python based web applications overseeing other developers as the technical authority. This included ecommerce systems, access and identity management including SSO, and database integration with MySQL and SQL Server. I also built and maintained Linux and Windows servers within the organisation's Infrastructure.



My initial role at the RCS was primarily a software development one, with additional content editing and SEO optimisation. During this time, I gained most of my front-end experience implementing designs using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Solicitors Own Software	Bath	June - September 2002	Junior Programmer

My work at Solicitors Own Software involved creating the client side of a SOAP/XML distributed application for Case and Practice Management. Our preliminary work included prototype Java development and switched to a .NET client in C# and VB.net.

(Freelance web	London	2001 – Present
development)		

My freelance web development has been based around Python and PHP, encompassing new site development in addition to consultancy and support. This includes building web sites and web applications for small businesses and organisations.

# **Qualifications**

2011	PRINCE2 Practitioner	APMG-International
2000-2004	BEng Computing (Hons)	City University, London
1998-2000	A' Level: Computing, Maths, and Physics	City of Bath College, Bath

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>i</sup> National Prospective Tonsillectomy Audit

<sup>&</sup>quot;Crane Database (www.crane-database.org.uk)

Patient Outcomes In Surgery (POIS) Audit

iv eSTEP Core (estepcore.rcseng.ac.uk) and Foundation (estepfdn.rcseng.ac.uk)